Guide to the Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, and Transgender Families Project, Yale Research Initiative on the History of Sexualities, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, and Transgender Families Project, Yale Research Initiative on the History of Sexualities, records
1990-2013
2012-2013
RU 1124
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.25
1 box
9675
The records consist of oral history interviews, reports, a timeline, and a small collection of printed materials documenting the history of the lesbian, gay, bisexual, and transgender (LGBT) family equality movement in the United States. Most of the individuals interviewed were associated with the following organizations: All Our Families Coalition; Center Families (New York City); Children of Lesbians and Gays Everywhere (COLAGE); Family Equality Council (Boston) and its predecessors (Gay Fathers Coalition and Gay and Lesbian Parents Coalition International); Fenway Health (Boston); Gay and Lesbian Adolescent Social Services (GLASS); Our Family Coalition (San Francisco Bay Area); and Rainbow Families (Minneapolis). Additional interviewees include attorneys and mental health and fertility services providers.
Yale Research Initiative on the History of Sexuality
Johnson, Emily Suzanne
Plaster, Joseph
Biographical / Historical
The Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, and Transgender (LGBT) Families Project was sponsored by the Yale Research Initiative on the History of Sexualities. The project was conducted by Emily Johnson and Joey Plaster, Yale University doctoral candidates, under the supervision of George Chauncey, Samuel Knight Professor of History and American Studies.
The goal of the project was to document the history of the LGBT family equality movement in the United States and focused on a few of the major support, advocacy and service organizations for gay, lesbian, bisexual, and transgender families. The project ran from summer 2012 to spring 2013.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred by the Yale Research Initiative on the History of Sexualities, 2012-2013.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of oral history interviews, reports, a timeline, and a small collection of printed materials documenting the history of the lesbian, gay, bisexual, and transgender (LGBT) family equality movement in the United States. Most of the individuals interviewed were associated with the following organizations: All Our Families Coalition; Center Families (New York City); Children of Lesbians and Gays Everywhere (COLAGE); Family Equality Council (Boston) and its predecessors (Gay Fathers Coalition and Gay and Lesbian Parents Coalition International); Fenway Health (Boston); Gay and Lesbian Adolescent Social Services (GLASS); Our Family Coalition (San Francisco Bay Area); and Rainbow Families (Minneapolis). Additional interviewees include attorneys and mental health and fertility services providers.
Arrangement
The records are aranged in two series: I. Oral history interviews, 2012-2013. II. Reports and historical documents, circa 1990-1912.
Conditions Governing Access
Some restrictions apply. Details provided at the file level.
Original computer files, as well as preservation masters, are restricted. Electronic files cannot be accessed remotely. Copies of the files are available in the repository.
Adoptive parents; Families; Gay fathers; Lesbian mothers; LGBTQ resource; COLAGE; Family Equality Council; Rainbow Families; All Our Families Coaltiion; Center Families (New York City); Fenway Health; Our Family Coalition
- Oral history interviews, 2012-2013; Series I
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically by last name of interviewee.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Original computer files, as well as preservation masters, are restricted. Electronic files cannot be accessed remotely. Copies of the files are available in the repository.
  - Appel, Judy, 2012 June 18
    Biographical / Historical
    Appel was, at the time of the interview, the executive director of Our Family Coalition in San Francisco, California.
    The materials are open for research.
    - Audiorecording, 1; ; 1.5 hours
    - Transcript, 1
  - Bergman, Kim, 2012 June 13
    Bergman was, at the time of the interview, co-owner of Fertility Counseling Services and Growing Connections.
    The material is closed to research pending receipt of oral history agreement.
    - Audiorecording, 1; ; 1 hour
    - Transcript, 1
  - Bradish, Chip, 2012 July 16
    Bradish was, at the time of the interview, a mental health counselor at Center Ground Counseling in Boston, Massachusettes.
    The material is closed to research pending transcript review by interviewee.
    - Audiorecording, 1; ; 59 minutes and 40 seconds
    - Transcript, 1
  - Carroll, Nina, 2012 July 11
    Carroll was a physician at Fenway Health, Boston Massachusettes.
    - Audiorecording, 1; ; 23 minutes and 28 seconds
    - Transcript, 1
  - Coolidge, Liz, 2012 July 12
    Coolidge was, at the time of the interview, the family and parenting coordinator for Fenway Health, in Boston, Massachusettes.
    - Audiorecording, 1; ; 1 hour, 6 minutes, and 5 seconds
    - Transcript, 1
  - Chrisler, Jennifer, 2013 January 31
    Chrisler is the former executive director of Family Equality Council in Boston, Massachusettes.
    - Audiorecording, 1; ; 44 minutes and 17 seconds
    - Transcript, 1
  - Davenport, Scott, 2012 March 29
    Davenport was a member of Gay and Lesbian Parents Coalition International (later Family Equality Council) and originator of Family Week, an lgbt family event in Provincetown, Massachusettes.
    - Audiorecording, 1; ; 1 hour, 9 minutes, and 35 seconds
    - Transcript, 1
  - Deaner, Cheryl, 2012 June 19
    Deaner is the founder of All Our Families Coalition in San Francisco, California.
    - Audiorecording, 1; ; 1 hour
    - Transcript, 1
  - DeCrescenzo, Terry, 2012 June 12
    DeCrescenzo is the founder of Gay and Lesbian Adolescent Social Services (GLASS) in Los Angeles, California.
    - Audiorecording, 1; ; 1.5 hours
    - Transcript, 1
  - Drew, Ray, 2013 May 15
    Drew was the first paid executive director of the Gay and Lesbian Parents Coalition (later the Family Equality Council).
    - Audiorecording, 1; ; 51 minutes and 50 seconds
    - Transcript, 1
  - Ferrera, Michael, 2012 June 12
    Ferrera is a former employee of Gay and Lesbian Adolescent Social Services (GLASS) in Los Angeles, California, and was, at the time of the interview, director of the GLBT Centers' LifeWorks program. He co-authored the Foster Care Non-Discrimination Act of 2004.
    - Audiorecording, 1; ; 1.5 hours
    - Transcript, 1
  - Fisher, Timothy Mark, 2013 May 8
    Fisher was the first executive director, Gay and Lesbian Parents Coalition International (later Family Equality Council).
    - Audiorecording, 1; ; 1 hour, 9 minutes, and 36 seconds
    - Transcript, 1
  - Gelnaw, Aimee, 2013 May 7
    Gelnaw was the second paid executive director of Parents Coalition International (later Family Equality Council).
    - Audiorecording, 1; ; 54 minutes and 2 seconds
    - Transcript, 1
  - Gogin, Kevin, and Dan McPherson, 2013 March 20
    Gogin was, at the time of the interview, program manager for San Franscisco Unified Schools. Dan McPherson counseled couples in private practice.
    - Audiorecording, 1; ; 1 hour
    - Transcript, 1
  - Greenfield, Dorothy, 2012 June 13
    Greenfield was, at the time of the interview, Clinical Professor of Obstetrics, Gynecology, and Reproductive Sciences, Yale Fertility Center, New Haven, Connecticut.
    - Audiorecording, 1; ; 1 hour, 19 minutes, and 28 seconds
    - Transcript, 1
  - Hanafin, Hilary, 2012 June 11
    Hanafin was, at the time of the interview, a clinical psychologist with the Center for Surrogate Parenting in Los Angeles, California.
    - Audiorecording, 1; ; 1.5 hours
    - Transcript, 1
  - Hecht-McGowen, Emily, 2012 July 13
    Hecht-McGowen was, at the time of the interview, the Director of Public Policy, Family Equality Council.
    - Audiorecording, 1; ; 32 minutes and 49 seconds
    - Transcript, 1
  - Jacobson, Linda, 2013 March 19
    Jacobson served on the board of Our Family Coalition.
    - Audiorecording, 1; ; 45 minutes
    - Transcript, 1
  - Kauffman, Joyce, 2013 May 15
    Kauffman was, at the time of the interview, a family attorney at Kauffman and Crozier and board member of GLAD (Gay and Lesbian Advocates and Defenders).
    - Audiorecording, 1; ; 44 minutes and 34 seconds
    - Transcript, 1
  - Logan, Jon, 2012 June 25
    Logan is the founder of Our Family in Berkeley, California.
    - Audiorecording, 1; ; 1.75 hours
    - Transcript, 1
  - Lorenz, Bill, 2012 July 16
    Lorenz was, at the time of the interview, director of finance and administration of Family Equality Council in Boston, Massachusettes.
    - Audiorecording, 1; ; 44 minutes and 19 seconds
    - Transcript, 1
  - Lynch, Stefan, 2013 March 12
    Lynch served as co-director of COLAGE (Children of Lesbians and Gays Everywhere).
    - Audiorecording, 1; ; 1.25 hours
    - Transcript, 1
  - Majors, Steve, 2012 July 12
    Majors was, at the time of the interview, communications director, Family Equality Council.
    - Audiorecording, 1; ; 7 minutes and 4 seconds
    - Transcript, 1
  - Meyers, Jen, 2012 July 20
    Meyers was, at the time of the interview, director of development for Family Equality Council in Boston, Massachusettes.
    - Audiorecording, 1; ; 16 minutes and 54 seconds
    - Transcript, 1
  - Miller-Shiell, Heather, 2013 April 1
    Miller-Shiell is a former board member of Rainbow Families in Minneapolis, Minnesota.
    - Audiorecording, 1; ; 46 minutes and 37 seconds
    - Transcript, 1
  - Nelson, Stephen, and Peter Vitale, 2012 August 26
    Nelson and Vitale are former board members of Rainbow Families in Minneapolis, Minnesota.
    - Audiorecording, 2; ; 51 minutes and 11 seconds
    - Transcript, 1
  - Nolan, Nick (pseudonym), 2012 June 11
    Nolan is a former employee of Gay and Lesbian Adolescent Social Services (GLASS) in Los Angeles, California.
    - Audiorecording, 1; ; 1.5 hours
    - Transcript, 1
  - Planck, Corri, 2013 May 17
    Planck was the first director of policy and public affairs and former deputy executive director of the Gay and Lesbian Parents Coalition International (later Family Equality Council).
    - Audiorecording, 1; ; 44 minutes and 5 seconds
    - Transcript, 1
  - Potter, Jennifer, 2012 July 13
    Potter was, at the time of the interview, director of Women's Health Center at Boston Beth Israel Deaconess Medical Center in Boston, Massachusettes.
    - Audiorecording, 1; ; 30 minutes and 21 seconds
    - Transcript, 1
  - Prochovnick, Ora, 2013 March 15
    Prochovnick was, at the time of the interview, an attorney who specialized in lesbian, gay, bisexual, and transgender family law.
    - Audiorecording, 1; ; 45 minutes
    - Transcript, 1
  - Robinson, Doug, 2012 August 26
    Robinson chaired the board of Center Families.
    - Audiorecording, 2; ; 1.75 hours
    - Transcript, 1
  - Rosen, Arielle, 2012 June 17
    Rosen is the former director of the LA Center's GLBT Family Services Program.
    - Audiorecording, 1; ; 1.5 hours
    - Transcript, 1
  - Ruby, Alice, 2013 March 18
    Ruby was, at the time of the interview, executive director of the Sperm Bank of California, Berkeley.
    - Audiorecording, 1; ; 1 hour
    - Transcript, 1
  - Simões, Rocki, 2012 August 29
    Simões was, at the time of the interview, involved with Host Home and Avenues for Youth in Minneapolis, Minnesota.
    - Audiorecording, 1; ; 1 hour, 15 minutes, and 53 seconds
    - Transcript, 1
  - Smidzik, Laura, 2012 August 31
    Smidzik was the second executive director of Rainbow Families in Minneapolis, Minnesota.
    - Audiorecording, 1; ; 52 minutes
    - Transcript, 1
  - Spiegel, Charlie, 2012 June 26
    Spiegal was a founder of Our Family Coalition.
    - Audiorecording, 2; ; 1.5 hours
    - Transcript, 1
  - Talen, Deborah, 2012 August 27
    Talen was the first executive director of Rainbow Families in Minneapolis, Minnesota.
    - Audiorecording, 1; ; 1 hour, 17 minutes, and 31 seconds
    - Transcript, 1
  - Teper, Beth, 2013 March 19
    Permission to access requires written permission from Beth Teper.
    Teper is a former executive director of COLAGE (Children of Lesbians and Gays Everywhere).
    - Audiorecording, 2; ; 45 minutes
    - Transcript, 1
  - Tisel, Betty, 2012 August 25
    Tisel is a former board member and newsletter editor for Rainbow Families in Minneapolis, Minnesota.
    - Audiorecording, 2; ; 47 minutes and 52 seconds
    - Transcripts, 1
  - Tyrrell, Gerry, 2012 August 22
    Tyrrell is a former Board Member, Rainbow Families in Minneapolis, Minnesota.
    - Audiorecording, 2; ; 53 minutes and 32 seconds
    - Transcript, 1
  - Vassar, Janice, 2012 August 28
    Vassar was a member of the board of Rainbow Families in Minneapolis, Minnesota.
    - Audiorecording, 1; ; 48 minutes and 52 seconds
    - Transcript, 1
  - Wald, Deborah, 2013 March 13
    Wald was, at the time of the interview, an attorney who specialized in lesbian, gay, bisexual, and transgender family law.
    - Audiorecording, 1; ; 45 minutes
    - Transcript, 1
  - Weltman, John J., 2012 July 9
    Weltman was, at the time of the interview, an attorney at Circle Surrogacy in Boston, Massachusettes.
    - Audiorecording, 2; ; 44 minutes and 17 seconds
    - Transcript, 1
  - White, Jacqueline, 2012 August 20
    White was a member of the board of Rainbow Families (Minneapolis, Minnesota) and Host Home.
    - Audiorecording, 2; ; 1 hour, 49 minutes, and 9 seconds
    - Transcript, 1
  - Wright, Brent, 2012 July 18
    Wright was, at the time of the interview, director of programming of Family Equality Council in Boston, Massachusettes.
    - Audiorecording, 1; ; 26 minutes and 11 seconds
    - Transcript, 1
- Reports and historical documents, Circa 1990-2012; Series II
  - Project records, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Consists of brief research reports on organizations and individuals relevant to the history of lesbian, gay, bisexual, and transgender family movement in the United States, which were compiled by Emily Johnson and Joey Plaster in preparation for conducting the oral history interviews. Also included are a spreadsheet with interview information (duplicated in the collection inventory) and a timeline: "Brief History of GLBT Parenting, with focus on the U.S."
  - Historical documents
    Consists of reports, articles, forms and survey responses given to the Emily Johnson for the archive, by a Gerry Tyrrell and a member of the Fenway Community Health.